Isabel **Neto**, PhD Candidate

■ isabel.canico.neto@gmail.com https://isabelcaniconeto.github.io/site/ https://github.com/isabelcaniconeto in www.linkedin.com/in/isabelcaneto

RESEARCH MISSION

To develop human-robot experiences to foster a better life for children with and without impairments, using technology to provide the same opportunities to all and a more diverse and inclusive society while enabling a seamless integration of robotic technologies into human environments.

My main research interests are: Social Robotics, Children Education, Accessibility, Inclusion, and Human-Robot Interaction.

ABOUT ME

A PhD Candidate in the Computer Science and Engineering, IST - Technical Institute from the University of Lisbon and researcher in GAIPS at INESC-ID. With a focus on social agents for inclusion in schools. Supervised by Prof. Ana Paiva and Prof. Hugo Nicolau prominent researchers in social robotics and accessibility fields. We are currently exploring the impact of that robot experience in children's interactions with each other in the long-term. And we are currently working closely with three local schools (Centro Helen Keller, Agrupamento Olaias e Agrupamento Sintra) in Portugal.

I am also a teacher assistant in Lisbon Tech Institute in HCI-Human Computer Interaction.

I am a computer science engineer, with 20 + years of experience in senior leadership, design, business, people management and digital transformation in Telecommunications Industry, in Vodafone. I have embraced several technical and management areas in Digital, Customer Operations and IT. Passionate about people, I managed people for over 16 years, collaborated with many talented people having a long experience in a customer-centric approach, leading design thinking methods to build and develop personalized and ethical experience in digital channels and assisted channels, such as social media platforms, chat and chat-bots, mobile applications and web sites for self-care, eCommerce and digital marketing campaigns.

I am, nowadays, investing in a doctoral program to deepen knowledge and skills in Artificial Intelligence, mainly on social robotics and human interaction.

EMPLOYMENT

Teacher Assistant IST - University of Lisbon

2021-Present

Computer Science Engineering
• Course: (BSc) Human Computer Interaction (Spring 2021)

Research Assistant | INESC-ID

2021-Present

GAIPS - "Research Group on AI for People and the Society, and "Visualization and Intelligent Multimodal Interfaces Group"

MSc Advisor IST - University of Lisbon

2020-Present

Co-advisor of three MSc in Social Robotics and Human-Computer Interactions

DIGITAL Manager and Senior Product Owner Vodafone

2018-2020

Responsible for the Digital Channel road-map, engagement, strategy, budget control, delivery web and mobile development, and UX-UI design, for eCommerce, customer care, search and assisted help (such as chat, chatbot and social media).

- App My Vodafone engagement, (13 + Millon visits per month)
- Customer satisfaction focus (NPS 35)
- · Digital tools implementation (Adobe Audience, Target and analytic, replay sessions, internal search engine

Head of Digital in Customer Operations Vodafone

2014-2018

Digital (UX-UI, self-care channels, digital tools analytic and search) and Billing Area (finishing and digital Invoice) and social media support.

- Digital engagement, (increase 5x of use of digital channels, 80% of customer use digital bill, 95% of all customer contacts made by these channels)
- · Sentiment analysis on social media

IT Delivery Manager - Online and Finance Projects | Vodafone

2011-2014

Vendor management (outsourcing ADM), Project and Program Management, Delivery manager for Strategic Projects (Online and Finance Area), Demand management and Budget control. Responsible for BI and Online Domain in Vodafone Portugal.

- Digital projects implementation (eShop, self-care web and single sign-on)
- Advisor for Oracle (Customer Advisory Board) for WebCenter platform and Speaker in Oracle Open World Conference (2014)
- Finance projects implementation (HP FMS Fraud, HP Data Retention, Callidus commissions system, Tallyman

IT Delivery Manager – Technical and Finance Projects | Vodafone

2008-2011

Vendor management, IT Program management for Fixed Line Offer, Demand management and Budget control. Responsible for BI Domain in Vodafone Portugal.

• Responsible for Fixed-line implementation and launch (FTTh launch, TV implementation and Shared Fixed Network with

- Responsible for Fixed-line implementation and launch (FTTh launch, TV implementation and Shared Fixed Network with Optimus)
- Finance Projects (RAID revenue assurance)

IT Manager - Analysis Team and Project Management | Vodafone

2006-2008

Vendor management (ADM), Program Management, Demand Management and Budget control.

- Responsible for Fixed-line ADSL implementation and launch
- managing the Business Analysis Team for BI, SAP, Commissions and Logistics Area,

IT Manager - ERP projects and support | Vodafone

2001-2006

• Launch of Bad debt projects, workflows and Document Management (Filenet)

IT Analyst and Project Manager | Telecel

1996-2001

· Launch of SAP R3 and Portability Project MGT, Abap development and Team Leader of a development team

EDUCATION

PhD Candidate in Computer Science and Engineering IST - University of Lisbon 2019-Present Fostering Inclusive Activities in Mixed-visual Abilities Classrooms using Social Robots. Supervised by Prof. Ana Paiva and Prof. Hugo Nicolau.

Computer Science and Engineering Degree IST - University of Lisbon

1990-1995

Leadership-Executive Education Nova SBE - University of Lisbon

2018-2018

Product Owner | Scrum Alliance certificate

2018-Present

Digital Marketing | Square-Google

2017-Present

Finance-Executive Education | Catholic University

2008

1996-Present

Enterprise Training

• SAP R/3, Callidus, BI, CRM-Siebel, Billing, ORACLE WebCenter, Adobe Analytics, Adobe Experience Management

· Design Thinking, People Management

PUBLICATION 1

Also see my Google Scholar, Research-Gate, and ACM profiles.

Conference Proceedings

- Neto, I., Paiva, A. and Nicolau, H. 2021. Community Based Robot Design for Classrooms with Mixed Visual Abilities Children. CHI '21: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (2021).
- Neto, I., Nicolau, H. and Paiva, A. 2021. Fostering Inclusive Activities in Mixed-visual Abilities Classrooms using Social Robots. Companion of the 2021 ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI '21 Companion) (2021).
- Neto, I., Johal, W., Couto, M., Nicolau, H., Paiva, A. and Guneysu, A. 2020. Using Tabletop Robots to promote Inclusive Classroom Experiences. IDC 2020- Proceedings of the 2020 ACM Conference on Interaction Design and Children (2020).
- Neto, I. 2020. Using Social Robots to Create Inclusive Classroom Experiences for Children with Mixed Visual Abilities. ASSETS 2020 22nd International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility DC (2020).

Workshop Proceedings

• Neto, I., Nicolau, H., Paiva, A. and Guneysu, A. 2020. Exploring the Challenges and Opportunities for Inclusive Social Robots in Classroom Activities through Participatory Design Activities. IDC 2020 Workshop - World's Most Inclusive PD Project(2020).

PRFSENTATIONS

Paper Presentations

- · Community Based Robot Design for Classrooms with Mixed Visual Abilities Children. CHI '21 (May 2021).
- Fostering Inclusive Activities in Mixed-visual Abilities Classrooms using Social Robots. HRI '21 Companion (March 2021).
- Using Social Robots to Create Inclusive Classroom Experiences for Children with Mixed Visual Abilities. ASSETS '20 Doctoral Consortium (Oct. 2020).
- Using Tabletop Robots to promote Inclusive Classroom Experiences. IDC '20 (June 2020).

Talks

- Can social robots be part of Diversity and Inclusion? Lean Circle (January 2021).
- The future of content management. Oracle Open World. San Francisco (May 2014).
- Web Center Sites for eCommerce in Telecommunication Industry. Oracle User Day ' (September 2013).

HONORS

- HRI '21 Pioneer (March 2021).
- ASSETS '20 Doctoral Consortium (October 2021).

COMMUNITY SERVICES

- Student Volunteer HRI '21 (March 2021).
- Student Volunteer ASSETS '20 (October 2021).
- Poster Paper reviewer HAI '20 (August 2020).
- ORACLE Customer Advisor Board (2013-2017).